Rohit Choudhary

Senior Salesforce Developer

Wayne, New Jersey USA

in sangryal (https://www.linkedin.com/in/sangryal/)



I am a professional with a Master's in Computer Applications (MCA) and over 8 years of extensive experience in Salesforce development and SAP Basis, specializing in Healthcare and Insurance domains. Proficient in Aura, Apex, LWC and SOQL.

SKILLS -

LanguagesFrameworksDatabasesApex | JavaScript | Java | CLWC | AURAMYSQLToolsCertificationsOtherGit | ANT | Jenkins | JiraSalesforce Admin | Salesforce PD1Leadership | Time Management

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jun 2023 - Current

Senior Salesforce Developer at Cognizant (Client:Zoetis)

Parsippany, USA

- Spearheaded as Onshore Lead for a critical support project, ensuring swift resolution of P1 and P2 incidents to minimize system downtime and maintain operational continuity.
- Proactively engaged with clients daily, fostering strong relationships and addressing key issues promptly to uphold service level agreements (SLAs).
- Led functional grooming sessions to refine new requirements, effectively translating business needs into actionable user stories for agile sprints.
- Coordinated and prioritized tasks within the team to ensure timely delivery of sprint commitments and alignment with project timelines
- Maintained comprehensive documentation of incidents, resolutions, and project progress, ensuring transparency and facilitating knowledge sharing across the organization.

Feb 2020 - Jun 2023

Senior Salesforce Developer at Cognizant (Client:Johnson & Johnson)

Pagaluru, India

- Developed and implemented Territory Model for Johnson & Johnson's sales representatives, enhancing efficiency and effectiveness of sales operations.
- Built an Asset tracker management system for the JNJ's sales representatives and integrated system with SAP.
- Led requirement gathering sessions, provided accurate estimations, and successfully delivered solutions using Agile methodologies, ensuring alignment with business objectives.
- Designed and deployed new Aura components, Apex classes, Batch classes, profiles, process builders, and streamlining business processes and improving operational workflows.
- Handled the deployment of the changes from one org to another org using ANT, change set and used Jenkins to commit.
- Performed the testing and prepared technical documentation.
- Daily stand- up calls with BA for any issues with the user stories and provided Support team handover at the end of each sprint.

Sep 2019 - Feb 2020

Salesforce Developer at Cognizant (Client:Johnson & Johnson)

Q Bengaluru, India

 Built a Salesforce Mobile supported application to handle the Book of Accounts, Opportunities, Contacts and many more for the JNJ sales representatives.

- Developed multiple Aura components, Apex classes, and Asynchronous classes for Salesforce mobile application.
- Involved in requirement gathering and prepared effort estimation document.
- Created custom objects, custom profiles, process builder and lightning flows.
- Rollout for the same application has been done for multiple markets.
- Client Communication on a daily/weekly basis.

Jun 2018 - Aug 2019

System Engineer at Tata Consultancy Services (Client:Prudential)

Q Chennai, India

- Built a Recommendation Tool to recommend different available policies to a client according to their requirements.
- Create Lightning Components, Apex classes, Test Classes and manage custom objects, fields and formulas.
- Configure, maintain, develop and support the salesforce.com application.
- Customize new and existing page layouts for individual business units within the organization.
- Client Communication on a daily/weekly basis.

Jun 2016 - Jun 2018

System Engineer-Trainee at Tata Consultancy Services (Client:Bayer)

Q Bengaluru, India

- Understand and develop roles for different markets.
- Worked on the rollout projec
- Analyze the requirement and implement on time with proper testing.

EDUCATION

2014 - 2016

Master Computer Application at Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore

2011 - 2014

Bachelor Computer Applications at Sri Guru Goving Singh College, Chandigarh

LANGUAGES

English

INTERESTS

Entertainment Mentoring

Skills acquired: Movies | Tv Series